BHAVIK GILBERT

Software Engineer

bhaviklob@hotmail.com

→ +447405805628

Bhavik Gilbert

Bhavik-Gilbert

Portfolio Website

EDUCATION

Computer Science BSc (Hons)



King's College London

2021 - 2024

Awards

- · Associate of King's College London
- Professional Skills for a Globalised World

CS50 Online



Harvard University

2022

A-Levels

Mathematics, Computer Science Physics, Economics

Leyton VI Form College

2019 - 2021

SKILLS

- Python
- 🛔 Java
- 😇 👸 HTML/XML/CSS
- **g** Javascript
- PHP
- **G C**/C++
- @ C#
- Scala
- 💆 SQL

AWARDS

- Forage JPMC & Co Software **Engineering Virtual Experience**
- Duke of Edinburgh Bronze & Silver
- OFQUAL Open Awards Entry 3 Award in Employability and Professional Development (RQF)
- OpenLearn Introduction to software development & Technological innovation: a resource-based view

REFERENCES

• edwin.nganga@leyton.ac.uk

PROFILE

Driven by my passion for Tech, I've pursued a range of experiences to expand my knowledge around it. As a result, I've dabbled in several fields including: data analysis, game development, machine learning, web development and database systems. Proceeding forward, I plan to continue developing my knowledge as a software developer, adapting alongside new technologies and design structures, further improving my problem-solving and algorithmic thinking.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Analyst (Software Engineer I)



JPMorgan Chase & co

September 2024 - Current

Fullstack Development & Data Science

- CIB Athena Core Devtools
- Python (Pandas | Bottle | Tornado) | Typescript (React) | SQL
- Worked on a codebase with over 50 million lines of code.

Graduate Teaching Assistant



King's College London

September 2023 - Current

- Module: 5CCS2PEP Practical Experiences of Programming
- Taught C++ and Scala

Software Engineer Analyst (Intern)



JPMorgan Chase & co

June 2023 - August 2023

Backend Development & Data Science

- CIB Athena Market Data
- Python (Pandas) | SQL
- Worked on a codebase with over 50 million lines of code.

Location Camp Manager



Funtech

July 2022 - August 2022

- Managed and supported staff across 7 on-site locations
- Courses: 3D Game Development(Unreal Engine 4), CyberSecurity(Kali Linux), Python(Basic/OOP/Pygame Development/AIML), Lego Robotics, Java(Basic)

PROJECTS

Deafblind Social Media Application

JPMorgan Code For Good Hackathon - NGO: DeafBlind UK

Group Project - 5 Contributors

- Python | SQL Social Media Web App (Flask | ColorBlind | PIL | CV2 | DeepFace)
- Social Media website designed for deafblind people
- Key Features: Facial Recognition Login, Google Sign-in, Image Colour Daltonization, Text to Speech, Image Magnification

Greggor Financial Companion

Group Project - 8 Contributors

- Python | Javascript Financial Tracker Web App (Django | PIL | Tabula | Pandas | Numpy)
- Financial tracker web application, enabling users to track expenditures across multiple banks, categories and currencies
- Key Features: Parsing Transactions from Bank Statement, Account Balance Projections, Finding Subscriptions, Financial Quiz

Phase Folding Kepler Exoplanet Luminosity

- Python | Data Analysis & Graphical Manipulation (Pandas | Numpy | Matplotlib)
- Calculating the radius and orbital period of an exoplanet from the change in luminosity of the star it's orbiting using phase folding.